# Ust Oldfield

Experienced Consultant with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Databases, Data Warehousing, Data Architecture, Data Modelling, Data Analytics, Big Data Architecture, DevOps, Data Visualisation and Predictive Modelling.

## CONTACT

Email	Phone Number	Address
uoldfield@gmail.com	+447969 021688	14 Woodside Road
		London
		SE25 5DY

## **EXPERIENCE**

October 2014 - Present	Principal	Consultant	and	London
	Architect -	Adatis		

At Adatis I am responsible for delivering some of the most technical analytics projects in the UK. Adatis are known for their ability to innovate and deploy bespoke analytical solutions for some of the UK's biggest companies. I specialise in delivering big data and analytical solutions.

Duties include, but not limited to:

- Working with stakeholders to discover requirements and design a solution around the requirements;
- Development lead, solution architect and primary account manager for a variety of clients
- Internal lead for DevOps; Research, Development and Innovation; and Technical Learning and Development

Recent projects for clients have included, but not limited to:

- Lead consultant and principal architect for a distributed analytical platform at Anglian Water Services (AWS). Implemented a fully capable solution utilising DevOps principles, including test automation; continuous integration and deployment. The objective of this project was to build a modern analytical platform, utilising the Azure estate, so that AWS could realise the potential of data coming from the following: sensors on their water supply infrastructure to identify leaks; vehicle telemetry data to improve the services provided to customers in response to engineering requests; and migrating an existing on-premises finance data warehouse to Azure.
- Lead consultant and architect for implementing a work force management system at HMRC so that HMRC could effectively allocate resources to deal with customer demand.
- Lead consultant for an Enterprise Data Warehouse at Diageo. This involved ingesting data from
  a variety of sources; cleaning and conforming the data; putting in place master data
  management, including a management and governance framework; designing and populating
  the data warehouse; and making data available to various down-stream systems via APIs.
- Lead consultant and principal architect for the development of a near-real time Data Warehouse and forecasting tool at Skanska so that Skanska to model and predict the profitability of the projects they bid for and successfully completed. In addition to this, we incorporated streaming data from piling rigs so that the potential cost of mis-drilling could be captured and rectified before the concrete set.
- Lead consultant for Enterprise roll-out and governance of Power BI at the Department for Education

Presented at various conferences both nationally and internationally

- Big Data LDN 2018 Power BI and Big Data
- SQL Saturday Plovdiv 2018 Tabular Automation with TMSL and PowerShell
- SQL Bits 2018 Tabular Automation with TMSL and PowerShell
- PASS Summit 2017 Deep Dive into Azure Data Lakes
- SQL Bits 2017 Deep Dive into Azure Data Lakes

<ul> <li>SQL Relay 2016 – Managin</li> </ul>	ng Azure Data Lakes	
May 2013 – October 2014	Analytics Manager – UMG	London

Collecting, collating and carrying out complex data analysis in support of management requests. Reporting statistical findings to colleagues and senior managers.

Duties included, but not limited to:

- Collecting and analysing data on consumer demographics, preferences, needs, and buying habits to identify potential markets and factors affecting product demand;
- Segmenting consumers based on attitudes and behaviour about music consumption;
- Using quantitative and qualitative data from consumer surveys to gain a deeper insight into consumer activity;
- Preparing reports of findings, illustrating data graphically and translating complex findings into written text;
- Analysing raw data, drawing conclusions & developing recommendations;
- Advising on the suitability of methodologies and suggesting improvements;
- Carrying out specified data processing and statistical techniques;
- Supplying qualitative and quantitative data to colleagues;
- Developing predictive models and k-means clustering using the big data sets we have access to;
- Forecasting and tracking trends in changes to consumers' attitudes and behaviour;
- Creating pricing models which factor in price elasticity for several products.

<u> </u>	'	'
July 2012 – May 2013	Analyst – EMI	London
Death-stocked and the second Best and the		

#### Duties included, but not limited to:

- Collecting and analysing data on consumer demographics, preferences, needs, and buying habits to identify potential markets and factors affecting product demand;
- Segmenting consumers based on attitudes and behaviour about music consumption;
- Using quantitative and qualitative data from consumer surveys to gain a deeper insight into consumer activity;
- Analysing raw data, drawing conclusions & developing recommendations;
- Carrying out specified data processing and statistical techniques;
- Supplying qualitative and quantitative data to colleagues;
- Forecasting and tracking trends in changes to consumers' attitudes and behaviour;
- Creating pricing models which factor in price elasticity for several products.

August 2011 – July 2012	Analyst – Romax	London

#### Duties included, but not limited to:

- Manipulating, cleansing & processing data using Excel and Access;
- Responsible for loading, extracting and validation of client data. Liaising with end-users and 3rd party suppliers;
- Analysing raw data, drawing conclusions & developing recommendations;
- Developing data analytical databases from complex financial source data;
- Performing daily system checks;
- Data entry, data auditing, creating data reports & monitoring all data for accuracy;
- Monitoring the automated loading processes;
- Advising on the suitability of methodologies and suggesting improvements;
- Carrying out specified data processing and statistical techniques;
- Supplying qualitative and quantitative data to colleagues & clients;
- Using SPSS to extract, transform & load source data from transaction systems.

• Using 5P55 to extract, transform & load source data from transaction systems.			
September 2005 – July 2011	Officer – British Army		

#### Duties included, but not limited to:

- Responsible for the welfare, morale and motivation of subordinates. Motivating and leading subordinates to achieve objectives, often in difficult and dangerous conditions;
- Communicating effectively with my unit, as well as with other colleagues and professional and community groups, both orally and in writing, through briefings, operational reports and presentations;

- Training and developing subordinates of all ranks and bringing them up to a high standard of operational readiness;
- Assessing the effectiveness of training;
- Identifying objectives and assessing ways of achieving them;
- Preparing or modifying operational strategies and plans;
- Allocating equipment, personnel and resources effectively to achieve objectives.

## **EDUCATION**

2009 – 2011	University of Exeter	MA Economic History
2006 – 2009	University of Reading	BA History and Economics

# QUALIFICATIONS

MCSE: Data Management and Analytics	June 2017
MCSA: SQL Server 2012/2014	December 2016
MCP: Microsoft Certified Professional	October 2015
Scrum Master	January 2015

## **PORTFOLIO**

My GitHub repository can be found here: <a href="https://github.com/uoldfield">https://github.com/uoldfield</a> and several technical blogs can be found here: <a href="http://blogs.adatis.co.uk/ustoldfield/">https://blogs.adatis.co.uk/ustoldfield/</a>

### **SKILLS**

**Industry Knowledge** 

• Business In	ntelligence
---------------	-------------

- Database Design
- Extract, Transform, Load (ETL)
- Software Development
- Performance Tuning
- Master Data
   Management
- DevOps
- DataOps
- Azure Big Data Architecture
- Change Management
- Project Management
- Agile Development and Scrum
- Data Analytics
- Data Engineering

#### **Tools & Technologies**

- T-SQL
- SSRS
- SSIS
- Power BI
- Excel
- C#
- SSAS
- PowerShell

- Python
- Spark
- Azure SQL Data Warehouse
- Azure Data Factory (V1 & V2)
- Azure Data Lake

- Azure Data Lake Analytics (USQL)
- Azure Streaming
- Azure Databricks
- Docker
- Azure DevOps
- Git

### **INTERESTS**

Outside of work, I like to keep up-to-date with what is happening in the industry, including new technology trends and self-learning, and keeping abreast with current affairs in the UK and around the world. I keep active by playing cricket, petanque and cycling.